const e="englishlit",a=200,n=25,o=[{id:149,question:"“ I don’t see how any mother who cares for the modesty of her daughter can coolly sit down there and defend such waywardness”. “way wardness” in the except above refers to  ",option:{a:"sexual immorality  ",b:"painting  ",c:"dancing  ",d:"disobedience "},section:"Question is  based  on Joe de Graft’s Sons and Daughters.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:150,question:"Aaron’s painting is purchased by an American collector for the sum of ",option:{a:"250 dollars  ",b:"220 pounds ",c:"260 cedis  ",d:"280 francs "},section:"Question is  based  on Joe de Graft’s Sons and Daughters.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:151,question:"James Ofosu is pleased with George because he studies ",option:{a:"Law  ",b:"Accountancy ",c:"Engineering   ",d:"Medicine "},section:"Question is  based  on Joe de Graft’s Sons and Daughters.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:152,question:"Joe de Graft’s Sons and daughters is an example of ",option:{a:"domestic comedy ",b:"dark comedy ",c:"restoration comedy ",d:"comedy of error"},section:"Question is  based  on Joe de Graft’s Sons and Daughters.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:153,question:"The central conflict in the play is about  ",option:{a:"Lawyer Bonu’s attempt to seduce Maanan  ",b:"career choice for James Ofosu’s children  ",c:"Hannah’s lack of respect for James  ",d:"Fosuwa’s bid to force Lawyer Bonu on Maanan"},section:"Question is  based  on Joe de Graft’s Sons and Daughters.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:154,question:"David Rubadiri in “An African Thunderstorm” paints a graphic picture of the Thunderstorm through  the use of ",option:{a:" simile and personification  ",b:" Irony and imagery",c:" hyperbole and rhyme ",d:"innuendo and satire "},section:"Question is based on African and Non-African Poetry  ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:155,question:"In Andrew Marvell’s “To his Coy mistress”, the poet adopts a consistent rhyming scheme of ",option:{a:"sestet    ",b:"Couplet ",c:" tercet  ",d:"free verse"},section:"Question is based on African and Non-African Poetry  ",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:156,question:"Mazisi Kunene is an African poet from  ",option:{a:"Ghana ",b:"Nigeria  ",c:"Malawi  ",d:"South Africa"},section:"Question is based on African and Non-African Poetry  ",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:157,question:"In T.S. Eliot’s “The Journey of the Magi”, the journey can be described as  ",option:{a:"delightful   ",b:"unnecessary ",c:"allegorical  ",d:"symbolic "},section:"Question is based on African and Non-African Poetry  ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:158,question:"The dominant figurative device  in Kobena Acquah’s “In the Navel of the Soul” is",option:{a:"metaphor   ",b:"assonance  ",c:"paradox   ",d:"euphemism "},section:"Question is based on African and Non-African Poetry  ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:159,question:'‘fellow wayfarer…what good news do you bring me?" The statement above is addressed by Meka to',option:{a:"the Commandant’s messenger ",b:"a passing dog   ",c:"a dove ",d:"Engamba "},section:"Question is  based on Ferdinand Oyono’s The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:160,question:"Gullet is so named by the natives because of his  ",option:{a:"razor-sharp wit  ",b:"long neck ",c:"closeness to the people ",d:"hostility "},section:"Question is  based on Ferdinand Oyono’s The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:161,question:"The medal in the novel is a symbol of  ",option:{a:"ungodliness   ",b:"victory   ",c:"admiration ",d:"deceit "},section:"Question is  based on Ferdinand Oyono’s The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:162,question:"In the Joys of Motherhood, the joy of a mother is predicated on having ",option:{a:"husband    ",b:"sons ",c:"daughters   ",d:"wealth "},section:"Question is based on Buchi Emecheta’s The Joys of Motherhood.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:163,question:"The protagonist of the novel is  ",option:{a:"Nwokocha Agbadi ",b:"Nnaife  ",c:"Nwakusor ",d:"Nnu Ego."},section:"Question is based on Buchi Emecheta’s The Joys of Motherhood.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:164,question:"From the conclusion of the novel, the author implies that ",option:{a:"rebellion is fruitless ",b:"opposition pays ",c:"two and two make four ",d:"knowledge gives freedom."},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eighty Four",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:165,question:"“It was an enormous  pyramidal structure of glittering white concret, soaring up, terrace after terrace, 300 metres into the air”.",option:{a:"Being described in the except above is  ",b:"The party secretariat",c:"O’ Brien’s  residence  ",d:"The ministry of truth "},section:"The Ministry of Plenty ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:166,question:"In the novel, Oceania is at war with  ",option:{a:"Romania   ",b:"Catalonia    ",c:"Eastasia ",d:"Rhodeia"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:167,question:"“Minipax” in the true sense means ",option:{a:"ministry of Truth ",b:"Ministry of Love  ",c:"Ministry of War  ",d:"Ministry of Plenty "},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eighty Four",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:168,question:"In the Newspeak language, “duckspeak” is a word that simultaneously  refers to ",option:{a:"love and admiration  ",b:"knowledge and ignorance  ",c:"now and then ",d:"abuse and praise "},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eighty Four",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:169,question:"Hermeneutics is an art of  ",option:{a:"Calculation  ",b:"exaggeration ",c:"composition  ",d:"interpretation "},section:"Question is based on General literary principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:170,question:"A poem written in unrhymed five stress lines is called  ",option:{a:"ballad  ",b:"Blank verse ",c:"sonnet      ",d:"Ode"},section:"Question is based on General literary principles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:171,question:"The type of sonnet that has an octave and a sestet has its origin in  ",option:{a:"England  ",b:"Spain ",c:"Portugal   ",d:"Italy"},section:"Question is based on General literary principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:172,question:"The tone of the excerpt above is  ",option:{a:"jubilant  ",b:"condemnatory ",c:"adulatory  ",d:"defiant "},section:`“We own this land 
 And the swamps
 The palms
 And the mangroves;
 We ‘ll die defending them”
 Tony Afejuku “Land Song”  
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:173,question:"The figurative devices in the excerpt above are  ",option:{a:"rhyme and metaphor  ",b:"alliteration and assonance  ",c:"repetition and simile  ",d:"rhyme and onomatopoeia "},section:`“Her voice is a shell borne by the waves to crack the egg my soul sorely craves”
Segun Adekoya  “Love Blues” 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"}],t={subject:e,status:200,total:25,data:o};export{o as data,t as default,a as status,e as subject,n as total};
